<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
]>

  <section id="sect-ARES">
    <title>ARES</title>
    <section>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <para>
	<indexterm>
	  <primary>Amateur Radio Emergency Services</primary>
	</indexterm>
	ARES is the "feet on the ground" side of ARPSC.  NTS is the behind the
	scenes engine that moves messages.  Because it is largely involved in
	local response, ARES is not often visible to NTS operators.  However, in
	the Michigan Section we have approxmately 2,000 ARES members.  It is a
	large, highly structured organization which works closely with the
	Michigan State Police, local emergency management, and many other public
	service and public safety organizations.
      </para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>ARES Structure</title>
      <para>
	ARES is organized along the State Police Districts.  There are 11
	District Emergency Coordinators reporting to the Section Emergency
	Coordinator.  These DECs represent the seven State Police Districts and
	the four National Weather Service offices in Michigan.
      </para>
      <para>
	Each of Michigan's 83 counties has an Emergency Coordinator who reports
	to the respective District Emergency Coordinator.  These ECs and DECs
	often have assistants with specific responsibilities.  SKYWARN is often
	closely associated with ARES, and many Assistant Emergency Coordinators
	serve as their county's SKYWARN coordinator.
      </para>
      <para>
	Each county has a local organization whose size and responsibilities
	vary widely depending on the size and needs of the county.  In some
	rural counties the organization may consist of only two or three
	members, while a larger county may boast hundreds of members.
      </para>
      <para>
	At each level, ARES officials are aligned with government officials, and
	often work closely with them.  The SEC works closely with the State
	Police Logistics Section Chief, the DECs work with MSP's District
	Coordinators, and the county ECs align with their individual county
	Emergency Manager.  Whenever possible, the appointments are made jointly
	between the Section Manager and the appropriate government official.
	DECs serving NWS offices are aligned with that office's Warning
	Coordination Meterologist.
      </para>

    </section>

  </section>
