<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
]>

  <section id="sect-DCP">
    <title>District Communications Plan</title>
    <section>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <para>
	<indexterm>
	  <primary>Communications Plan</primary>
	</indexterm>
	One obvious failure that was exposed is the lack of adequate
	plans for communications among the counties in a District.
	Certainly there has been discussion, and also discussion about
	communications between Districts.  But before we develop between
	District plans, we need to have the problem solved within a
	District.
      </para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Call Trees</title>
      <para>
	<indexterm>
	  <primary>Call Tree</primary>
	</indexterm>
	Many counties, and even a few Districts, have call trees
	established, although these are rarely up to date.  Certainly,
	we should use every technology at our disposal, and the
	telephone is a common, and reliable mode.
      </para>
      <para>
	However, this mode will not work if the numbers are out of date,
	if we only have home numbers and people are away from their
	phones, or, of course, if the phones are out.  These systems
	need to be tested frequently, but backup mechanisms must also be
	in place.
      </para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Pagers</title>
      <para>
	<indexterm>
	  <primary>pagers</primary>
	</indexterm>
	Many programs have pagers, either provided by their counties, or
	developed by the programs themselves.  Pagers tend to be more reliable
	than cellular systems, but few, if any, Districts have paging systems
	for all the counties in the District.
      </para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Email Notification</title>
      <para>
	<indexterm>
	  <primary>Email Notification</primary>
	</indexterm>
	Most, if not all, Districts have email lists for notifying the various
	ECs of an event.  However, email is not real time, and most ECs do not
	have mobile email devices, so email is not appropriate for notfication
	of an incident.  In addition, many types of incidents can impact local
	Internet connections (although widespread Internet outages are virtually
	unheard of).
      </para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Text Messaging</title>
      <para>
	<indexterm>
	  <primary>Text Messaging</primary>
	</indexterm>
	In cases where all ECs have cellular telephones, notifications based on
	text messaging can be effective.  However, keep in mind that in the
	event of an actual incident, or even a high profile exercise, cellular
	systems will fail almost immediately, so this method is of limited use
	in the event of an actual incident.
      </para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Repeater Systems</title>
      <para>
	<indexterm>
	  <primary>Repeater Systems</primary>
	</indexterm>
	Many programs have some sort of scheme for notification by repeater, and
	in most cases, the various counties in a District are at least aware of
	the frequencies of repeaters in adjacent counties, so when the repeater
	infrastructure is unaffected, repeaters are of course useful tools.
      </para>
      <para>
	However, repeaters often have their vulnerabilities.  Often, they are
	higher profile than home stations, so are more likely to be affected by
	some kinds of weather events.  Repeaters are often isolated, and may not
	be in hardened sites, so can be affected by vandalism and other human
	caused incidents.  Repeaters often have some backup power, but
	frequently that backup power is limited.
      </para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Simplex Systems</title>
      <para>
	<indexterm>
	  <primary>Simplex Systems</primary>
	</indexterm>
	Most programs do not have reliable simplex systems thought out, but
	certainly, they offer the potential for greater robustness than most
	other systems.  To be effective, however, all parties need to know what
	is expected.
      </para>
      <para>
	Some things to consider:
	<itemizedlist spacing="compact">
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
	      There must be a prearranged and well communicated plan for
	      frequencies to be used
	    </para>
	  </listitem> 
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
	      There must be a prearranged schedule
	    </para>
	  </listitem> 
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
	      Each key station should be able to operate for an extended period
	      of time removed from commercial mains
	    </para>
	  </listitem> 
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
	      Each key station should have a backup plan in the event of antenna
	      damage or equipment malfunction
	    </para>
	  </listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
	<warning>
	  <title>The plan must be communicated</title>
	  <para>
	    No plan can be effective unless all affected parties are well aware
	    of the content of the plan and are capable of implementing it
	  </para>
	</warning>
      </para>
    </section>
  </section>
