<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
]>

  <section id="sect-Objectives">
    <title>Exercise Objectives</title>
    <section>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <para>
	The point of any exercise should be to accomplish something.  This
	section outlines some of the key objectives for the current exercise.
      </para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Structured Communications</title>
      <para>
	<indexterm>
	  <primary>Objectives</primary>
	  <secondary>Structured Communications</secondary>
	</indexterm>
	<indexterm>
	  <primary>Communications Structure</primary>
	</indexterm>
	The October 2009 SET had intended to demonstrate a structured flow of
	messages between the counties and the State EOC, along existing chain of
	command lines.  (If you will recall, an earlier exercise along an
	incident-specific structure elicited some significant complaints.)
      </para>
      <para>
	The results were not encouraging. Only one of the section nets organized
	as expected, and few counties or Districts attempted to exploit the NTS
	structure.  The exercise structure did leave the nets a lot of
	opportunity to apply their own creativity, but apparently the intent was
	insufficiently clear.
      </para>
      <para>
	<indexterm>
	  <primary>Net Schedule</primary>
	</indexterm>
	For this exercise, net schedules and message paths will be detailed
	ahead of time.  Each section net has a schedule and specified liaisons.
	Each District has specified liaisons.  There will still need to be some
	thought applied to the interface between the District and the
	appropriate VHF net, but both responsible parties are known well ahead
	of time.
      </para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Net Response Plan</title>
      <para>
	<indexterm>
	  <primary>Objectives</primary>
	  <secondary>Response Plan</secondary>
	</indexterm>
        Over recent years, it appears that nets have lost the ability or
        incentive to be able to mobilize in response to an incident.  Nets are
        accustomed to meeting at a specific time and frequency and somehow are
        not prepared to change.
      </para>
      <para>
	However, when an incident occurs, the National Traffic System is a vital
	part of the overall response.  ARES units are structured to respond
	locally, and their communications capability is largely local.  They
	require the services of NTS for longer haul communications, as well as
	to provide structure in the event of a heavy communications load.
      </para>
      <para>
	This exercise will only take a small step in the direction of giving the
	nets the skills needed.  There will be more interfaces with the ARES
	organization, and an opportunity will be given for close leadership
	cooperation between ARES and NTS.
      </para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>ARES Familiarity</title>
      <para>
	<indexterm>
	  <primary>Amateur Radio Emergency Services</primary>
	  <secondary>Familiarity with</secondary>
	</indexterm>
	<indexterm>
	  <primary>Objectives</primary>
	  <secondary>ARES Familiarity</secondary>
	</indexterm>
        Most net managers have little opportunity in ordinary circumstances to
	interface with ARES organizations.  However, familiarity with the
	individuals involved and their capabilities is vital if NTS is to offer
	needed services in the event of an incident.  This exercise will give
	NTS leaders some exposure to ARES leaders.  Especially in the case of
	the VHF nets, they will need to work closely to be successful.
      </para>
      <para>
	This, of course, is not sufficient, but it is a start.  Net managers
	should begin thinking about issues such as:
	<itemizedlist>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
	      What might my net be called on to do in the event of some kind of
	      incident or emergency
	    </para>
	  </listitem>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
	      How will I notify my members in the event of an unexpected net
	      activation
	    </para>
	  </listitem>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
	      If I need to activate at a different time of day, will I know how
	      to respond to different band conditions
	    </para>
	  </listitem>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
	      Do I know which net members might be available if we have a net
	      meeting at a time different than normal
	    </para>
	  </listitem>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
	      For VHF nets, do I have a plan to respond in the event my
	      repeater is out of service
	    </para>
	  </listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
	These are only a few of the questions net managers should begin thinking
	about.  This exercise will not answer these questions, but we hope to
	begin providing the insight necessary for the nets to begin grappling
	with them.
      </para>
    </section>

</section>
