<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
]>

  <section id="sect-NTS">
    <title>NTS</title>
    <section>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <para>
	<indexterm>
	  <primary>National Traffic System</primary>
	</indexterm>
	<indexterm>
	  <primary>Traffic Handling</primary>
	</indexterm>
	Messages are carried across North America, and across the Section, by
	the National Traffic System.  NTS operators practice constantly and as a
	result, are highly skilled at transmitting messges.
	<note>
	  <title>Practice makes perfect:
	    In contrast to ARES operators who exercise only occasionally, many
	    NTS operators practice their skill <emphasis>every day</emphasis>.
	  </title><para>&nbsp;</para>
	</note>
      </para>
      <para>
	Of course, it is "common knowledge" that "NTS is dying", but here in the
	Michigan Section, at least, NTS traffic has
	<emphasis>increased</emphasis> every year since at least 2005 (the
	earliest year for which the section has data).
      </para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Why should ARES use NTS</title>
      <para>
	Since NTS operators have the skill, it only makes sense to use the best
	possible service.  Obviously, NTS has little to offer for the local,
	tactical communications that make up perhaps 99% of the communications
	needed for any incident.  But when traffic needs to leave the county,
	then it only makes good sense to rely on those who do it every day.
	This also keeps resources free for urgent local needs.
      </para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>The structure of NTS</title>
      <para>
	<indexterm>
	  <primary>National Traffic System</primary>
	  <secondary>Structure of</secondary>
	</indexterm>
	NTS is structured into a series of layered nets.  Each level sends a
	representative to the higher level.  Net schedules are arranged to
	facilitate the rapid distribution of traffic across the system.  The
	five layers of NTS nets are:
	<itemizedlist>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
	      Local nets
	    </para>
	  </listitem>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
	      <indexterm>
		<primary>Section Nets</primary>
	      </indexterm>
	      <indexterm>
		<primary>Nets</primary>
		<secondary>Section</secondary>
	      </indexterm>
	      Section nets
	    </para>
	  </listitem>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
	      <indexterm>
		<primary>Region Nets</primary>
	      </indexterm>
	      <indexterm>
		<primary>Nets</primary>
		<secondary>Region</secondary>
	      </indexterm>
	      Region nets
	    </para>
	  </listitem>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
	      <indexterm>
		<primary>Area Nets</primary>
	      </indexterm>
	      <indexterm>
		<primary>Nets</primary>
		<secondary>Area</secondary>
	      </indexterm>
	      Area nets
	    </para>
	  </listitem>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
	      <indexterm>
		<primary>Transcontinental Corps</primary>
	      </indexterm>
	      The Transcontinental Corps
	    </para>
	  </listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
	<indexterm>
	  <primary>Eighth Region Net</primary>
	</indexterm>
	<indexterm>
	  <primary>Eastern Area Net</primary>
	</indexterm>
	Local nets send a representative to the Section nets.  A Michigan
	representative to the Eighth Region net (8RN) is designated for each
	meeting of 8RN to carry traffic from the Section nets to the Eighth
	Region.  8RN in turn sends a representative to the Eastern Area net
	(EAN).  Transcontinental Corps (TCC) members then carry traffic between
	the areas, where it is then distributed downwards through the same
	structure until it can be delivered.
      </para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Michigan NTS Nets</title>
      <para>
	<indexterm>
	  <primary>Nets</primary>
	  <secondary>Michigan</secondary>
	</indexterm>
	<indexterm>
	  <primary>Michigan Nets</primary>
	</indexterm>
	Michigan has four affiliated VHF nets and seven HF nets.  These nets,
	their net managers, frequencies and schedules are available at <ulink
	type="http"
	url="http://www.mi-nts.org/netinfo.php">http://www.mi-nts.org/netinfo.php</ulink>.
      </para>
      <para>
	The VHF nets tend to be oriented toward training, although they handle
	substantial amounts of traffic.  Some of the HF nets, notably QMN and
	MITN, are somewhat "hard core", focusing solely on traffic and generally
	having very short sessions.  The others are more general nets where
	traffic is passed but that is not the sole purpose of the net.
      </para>
      <para>
	Although there are significant month to month variations, Michigan nets
	report handling between 600 and 1000 messages each month, with
	approximately two-thirds of that handled by QMN, MITN and MVTN.
      </para>
    </section>
  </section>
