<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
]>

  <section id="sect-Objectives">
    <title>Exercise Objectives</title>
    <section>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <para>
	The point of any exercise should be to accomplish something.  This
	section outlines some of the key objectives for the current exercise.
      </para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Structured Communications</title>
      <para>
	<indexterm>
	  <primary>Objectives</primary>
	  <secondary>Structured Communications</secondary>
	</indexterm>
	<indexterm>
	  <primary>Communications Structure</primary>
	</indexterm>
	The October 2009 SET had intended to demonstrate a structure flow of
	messages between the counties and the State EOC, along existing chain of
	command lines.  (If you will recall, an earlier exercise along an
	incident-specific structure elicited some significant complaints.)
      </para>
      <para>
	The results were not encouraging. Only one of the section nets organized
	as expected, and few counties or Districts attempted to exploit the NTS
	structure.  The exercise structure did leave the Districts a lot of
	opportunity to apply their own creativity, but apparently the intent was
	insufficiently clear.
      </para>
      <para>
	<indexterm>
	  <primary>Net Schedule</primary>
	</indexterm>
	For this exercise, net schedules and message paths will be detailed
	ahead of time.  Each section net has a schedule and specified liaisons.
	Each District has specified liaisons.  There will still need to be some
	thought applied to the interface between the District and the
	appropriate VHF net, but both responsible parties are known well ahead
	of time.
      </para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>District Communications Plan</title>
      <para>
	<indexterm>
	  <primary>Objectives</primary>
	  <secondary>Communications Plan</secondary>
	</indexterm>
	<indexterm>
	  <primary>Communications Plan</primary>
	</indexterm>
	During the 2009 SET it also became evident that not all Districts have
	thoroughly thought through within-District communications paths.  This
	issue is discussed in more detail in a later section.
      </para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>NTS Familiarity</title>
      <para>
	<indexterm>
	  <primary>National Traffic System</primary>
	  <secondary>Familiarity with</secondary>
	</indexterm>
	<indexterm>
	  <primary>Objectives</primary>
	  <secondary>NTS Familiarity</secondary>
	</indexterm>
	Although most communications in any incident is local, and most of that
	is tactical, strategic communications, whether local or otherwise,
	requires a higher level of discipline.  NTS procedures and structures
	provide that discipline within amateur radio.
      </para>
      <para>
	Each program requires at least a few people that are familiar with the
	existing NTS network and how it works.  There is a summary later in this
	document.  All individuals operating in ARES/RACES should have at least
	some familiarity with NTS procedures.  There is significant NTS training
	happening around the Section so at least a few individuals capable of
	passing NTS formatted messages should already be available within each
	program. 
      </para>
    </section>

</section>
