<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Michigan_2010_Summary.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
  <section id="sect-ARES">
    <title>Amateur Radio Emergency Service</title>
    <para>
      ARES represents the largest program.  ARES has a program in each Michigan
      county, managed by an Emergency Coordinator who works closely with the
      Emergency Management Director of the county to provide backup
      communications to the local jurisdiction.
    </para>
    <para>
      Because Michigan counties are so varied, the ARES organizations within
      those counties are quite varied.  Although their primary customer is
      typically the county Emergency Management organization, they may also work
      with the local Red Cross, Salvation Army, and other NGOs.  In some
      counties, the liaison with the fire departments or Sheriff's office is
      especially close.  Each county has different needs, and the ARES
      organization attempts to meet those needs.
    </para>
    <para>
      In Michigan, and especially southern Michigan, severe weather is common,
      and in many cases, the greatest effort is expended with weather related
      activities.  Amateurs spot bad weather and report to their National
      Weather Service office when bad weather is approaching, and following
      severe weather, are often involved in recovery operations.
    </para>
    <para>
      Late spring and early summer tend to be the time when damaging weather is
      encountered, and this is also the time that many organizations hold runs,
      walks and other events for which amateurs frequently provide
      communications.  Hence, the peaks in the middle of the year in the graph
      below: 
      <figure float="0"><title>Michigan ARES Hours</title>
	<mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
	    <imagedata scale="99" scalefit="1"
              fileref="images/FSD212.png" format="PNG"/>
	  </imageobject>
	  <textobject>
	    <para>
	      FSD-212 Results
	    </para>
	  </textobject>
	</mediaobject>
      </figure>
      Michigan ARES programs reported 55,087 hours in 2010, 7035 of them
      occuring in June.  2010 was a very light year for damaging weather.  In
      2009, when the state experienced much severe weather, more than twice that
      effort was reported in May alone, with all the late spring/early summer
      months exceeding June of 2010.
    </para>
    <section>
      <title>Organization</title>
      <para>
	The Michigan State Police divides the state into 7 Districts, and
	appoints a District Coordinator for each.  ARES has a District Emergency
	Coordinator for each of those districts, who works with the District
	coordinator.  In addition, the Section appoints a District Emergency
	Coordinator for each of the National Weather Service offices in the
	state.  This NWS DEC works with the office's Warning Coordination
	Meteorologist to provide training to SKYWARN members and implement
	circuits that permit field observations to be transmitted to the NWS
	office effectively.
      </para>
      <para>
	These DECs are as follows:
	<table frame="all" id="tbl-DEC">
	  <title>District Emergency Coordinators</title>
	  <tgroup cols="3">
	    <thead>
	      <row>
		<entry>District</entry>
		<entry>DEC Call</entry>
		<entry>DEC Name</entry>
	      </row>
	    </thead>
	    <tbody>
	      <row>
		<entry>1</entry>
		<entry>K8YZA</entry>
		<entry>Joe Pullen</entry>
	      </row>
	      <row>
		<entry>2</entry>
		<entry>K8UP</entry>
		<entry>John Fleming</entry>
	      </row>
	      <row>
		<entry>3</entry>
		<entry>N8OSL</entry>
		<entry>Joe Tuscher</entry>
	      </row>
	      <row>
		<entry>5</entry>
		<entry>KB8FQJ</entry>
		<entry>Carl Flickinger</entry>
	      </row>
	      <row>
		<entry>6</entry>
		<entry>KB8VEE</entry>
		<entry>Tom van der Mel</entry>
	      </row>
	      <row>
		<entry>7</entry>
		<entry>WA8RLI</entry>
		<entry>Red Duggan</entry>
	      </row>
	      <row>
		<entry>8</entry>
		<entry>KG8NK</entry>
		<entry>Lou Gembolis</entry>
	      </row>
	      <row>
		<entry>APX</entry>
		<entry>KC8YTK</entry>
		<entry>Chris Stinson</entry>
	      </row>
	      <row>
		<entry>DTX</entry>
		<entry>N8ZSA</entry>
		<entry>Ted Davis</entry>
	      </row>
	      <row>
		<entry>GRR</entry>
		<entry>N8VLN</entry>
		<entry>Michael Gage</entry>
	      </row>
	      <row>
		<entry>MQT</entry>
		<entry>KI8AF</entry>
		<entry>Greg Hanson</entry>
	      </row>
	    </tbody>
	  </tgroup>
	</table>
	In addition, the Section Emergency Coordinator maintains a small staff
	to help organize the section.  These assistant SECs are:
	<table frame="all" id="tbl-ASEC">
	  <title>Assistant Section Emergency Coordinators</title>
	  <tgroup cols="3">
	    <thead>
	      <row>
		<entry>Role</entry>
		<entry>ASEC Call</entry>
		<entry>ASEC Name</entry>
	      </row>
	    </thead>
	    <tbody>
	      <row>
		<entry>SEOC Alternate</entry>
		<entry>N8ERF</entry>
		<entry>Dr. Dennis Klipa</entry>
	      </row>
	      <row>
		<entry>SEOC Station Manager</entry>
		<entry>K8RDN</entry>
		<entry>Robert Berger</entry>
	      </row>
	      <row>
		<entry>Training and Exercises</entry>
		<entry>NX8A</entry>
		<entry>John (Jack) Hutcheson</entry>
	      </row>
	    </tbody>
	  </tgroup>
	</table>
      </para>
    </section>
  </section>
