<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Michigan_2010_Summary.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
  <section id="sect-Individual">
    <title>Individual Amateur Reporting</title>
    <para>
      In addition to reporting by Emergency Coordinators and Net Managers,
      individual amateurs are also encouraged to make reports.  There are three
      reports from individuals; Public Service Honor Roll, Station Activity
      Report, and Brass Pounder's League.
    </para>
    <section>
      <title>Public Service Honor Roll</title>
      <para>
	The Public Service Honor Roll reporting combines activity in a number of
	categories.  Stations get "points" for net checkins, traffic, Section
	level appointments, public service oriented web or other digital
	systems, and hours spent in public or emergency service.
      </para>
      <para>
	If a station reports 70 points within a month, that station is listed in
	QST, the amateur radio journal.  If a station is listed for 12
	consecutive months, or for 18 months out of 24, the League will issue a
	certificate.
      </para>
      <para>
	PSHR reporting for 2010 has been relatively flat across the year.  The
	summer months tend to be higher due to bad weather and various public
	service events.
	<figure float="0"><title>Public Service Honor Roll Reporting</title>
	<mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
	    <imagedata scale="99" scalefit="1"
              fileref="images/PSHR.png" format="PNG"/>
	  </imageobject>
	  <textobject>
	    <para>
	      PSHR Results
	    </para>
	  </textobject>
	</mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Station Activity Reports</title>
      <para>
	Stations handling traffic are encouraged to submit Station Activity
	Reports (SAR) indicating the amount of traffic handled.  Only 31
	stations reported during 2010.
      </para>
      <para>
	Since most of the traffic is handled by relatively few stations, and
	those stations tend to be the stations that report, the traffic totals
	reported are quite high.  Stations handling a lot of traffic tend to be
	those stations that act as liaisons to Region or Area nets, so even
	though the number of stations reporting is quite small, the amount of
	traffic reported is considerably larger than the totals from net
	reports, which include only messages passed on Michigan nets.  For 2010,
	Michigan stations individually reported 35,423 messages.
	<figure float="0">
	  <title>Station Activity Reports</title>
	  <mediaobject>
	    <imageobject>
	      <imagedata scale="99" scalefit="1"
		fileref="images/SAR-by-call.png" format="PNG"/>
	    </imageobject>
	    <textobject>
	      <para>
		SAR Results
	      </para>
	    </textobject>
	  </mediaobject>
	</figure>
      </para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Brass Pounder's League</title>
      <para>
	Stations reporting 500 messages passed in a single month, or a total of
	100 originations plus deliveries are eligible for Brass Pounder's
	league.  This requires substantial dedication, and only a few stations
	achieve this award.
      </para>
      <para>
	The stations qualifying in 2010 were:
	<table frame="all" id="tbl-BPL">
	  <title>Brass Pounder's League</title>
	  <tgroup cols="3">
	    <thead>
	      <row>
		<entry>Call</entry>
		<entry>Name</entry>
		<entry>Total</entry>
	      </row>
	    </thead>
	    <tbody>
	      <row>
		<entry>WB8WKQ</entry>
		<entry>Jeff Miller</entry>
		<entry>9010</entry>
	      </row>
	      <row>
		<entry>WB9JSR</entry>
		<entry>John Wehmer</entry>
		<entry>8287</entry>
	      </row>
	      <row>
		<entry>K8LJG</entry>
		<entry>John Kroll</entry>
		<entry>1285</entry>
	      </row>
	      <row>
		<entry>K8CQF</entry>
		<entry>Joe Turner</entry>
		<entry>101</entry>
	      </row>
	    </tbody>
	  </tgroup>
	</table>
      </para>
    </section>
  </section>
