<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Michigan_2010_Summary.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>

<section id="sect-NewMedia">
    <title>New Media</title>
    <para>
      The section utilizes a number of electronic media to communicate with
      members and potential members.
    </para>
    <section>
      <title>Electronic Mail</title>
      <para>
	The Section Emergency Coordinator maintains an email list of all
	Emergency Coordinators and District Emergency coordinators and uses this
	as a primary means of direct communications with the ECs.  The Section
	Traffic Manager maintains a similar list of Net Managers.
      </para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Web</title>
      <para>
	ARPSC maintains two web sites, one for ARES and one for NTS.
	There is also a Section web site for more general information, and a web
	site maintained by the Digiral Radio Group.
	<table frame="all" id="tbl-web">
	  <title>Web Sites</title>
	  <tgroup cols="3">
	    <thead>
	      <row>
		<entry>Site</entry>
		<entry>URL</entry>
		<entry>Content</entry>
	      </row>
	    </thead>
	    <tbody>
	      <row>
		<entry>Michigan Section</entry>
		<entry>
		  <ulink type="http" url="http://arrl-mi.org" />
		</entry>
		<entry>
		  Section news of general interest to amateurs in the Michigan
		  Section 
		</entry>
	      </row>
	      <row>
		<entry>Amateur Radio Emergency Services</entry>
		<entry>
		  <ulink type="http" url="http://www.mi-arpsc.org" />
		</entry>
		<entry>
		  Reference information of interest to ARES members, as well as
		  performance data
		</entry>
	      </row>
	      <row>
		<entry>National Traffic System</entry>
		<entry>
		  <ulink type="http" url="http://www.mi-nts.org" />
		</entry>
		<entry>
		  Reference information of interest to NTS members, as well as
		  performance data
		</entry>
	      </row>
	      <row>
		<entry>Digital Radio Group</entry>
		<entry>
		  <ulink type="http" url="http://www.mi-drg.org" />
		</entry>
		<entry>
		  Reference information concerning various digital modes,
		  especially packet.
		</entry>
	      </row>
	    </tbody>
	  </tgroup>
	</table>
      </para>
      <para>
	The screenshot below shows an example page from the mi-arpsc site.
	<figure float="0">
	  <title>mi-arpsc Website</title>
	  <mediaobject>
	    <imageobject>
	      <imagedata scale="50" scalefit="1"
		fileref="images/ARPSC-website.png" format="PNG"/>
	    </imageobject>
	    <textobject>
	      <para>
		ARPSC website
	      </para>
	    </textobject>
	  </mediaobject>
	</figure>
      </para>
      <para>
	In addition to the Section sites, many Districts and Nets also maintain
	web sites.
      </para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Blogs</title>
      <para>
	The Section Emergency Coordinator also maintains a blog, however this
	mode has proven to be of limited utility.  Much of the information
	that the SEC must communicate with ARPSC members has to do with the
	emergency planning of the State of Michigan.  This information should
	not be widely distributed, and blogs are easily located by search
	engines.  As a result, blog entries have been relatively sparse.
      </para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Online Social Groups</title>
      <para>
	The Section also maintains two Yahoo groups, the
	<filename>MIARPSC</filename> group is available to all Michigan
	amateurs, and is often useful for a number of discussions.  The
	<filename>MIARPSC-DEC</filename> group is private to DECs and ADECs, and
	is used for discussions within a smaller group.
      </para>
      <para>
	As with websites, many Districts and nets have found it helpful to
	maintain their own groups, most of these also on Yahoo.
      </para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Microblogging</title>
      <para>
	The section maintains two microblogging accounts;
	<filename>miarpsc</filename> on <filename>identi.ca</filename> and
	<filename>mi_arpsc</filename> on <filename>twitter.com</filename>.
	"Tweets" or "dents" are sent to these sites periodically to remind
	followers of various upcoming events.  Both sites get exactly the same
	feed.  There is also a page on the mi-arpsc web site, <ulink type="http"
	url="http://www.mi-arpsc.org/arpsc_tweets.php" />  where those who do
	not follow either microblogging site may view the feed.
	<figure float="0"><title>ARPSC Twitter Feed</title>
	  <mediaobject>
	    <imageobject>
	      <imagedata scale="50" scalefit="1"
		fileref="images/Twitter.png" format="PNG"/>
	    </imageobject>
	    <textobject>
	      <para>
		Twitter Feed
	      </para>
	    </textobject>
	  </mediaobject>
	</figure>
      </para>
      <para>
	The section tries to keep the volume to a few tweets a week to
	prevent followers from feeling that the feed is too burdensome.  Many of
	the tweets use the <filename>#hamr</filename> hash tag, causing those
	that follow amateur radio tweets to also see the messages.
      </para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Online Meetings</title>
      <para>
	Meetings within smaller groups are often held remotely.  Simple phone
	conferences are frequently used.  In addition, <filename>GoTo
	Meeting</filename>, and more recently, <filename>Vyew</filename> allow
	documents to be shared online during these phone conferences.
      </para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Wiki</title>
      <para>
	The section also maintains a wiki which is used by the ARPSC leadership
	to develop certain plans and strategies.  A wiki allows all participants
	to contribute asynchronously to a "document", which in many cases can be
	helpful. 
	<figure float="0"><title>Example Wiki Page</title>
	  <mediaobject>
	    <imageobject>
	      <imagedata scale="50" scalefit="1"
		fileref="images/Wiki.png" format="PNG"/>
	    </imageobject>
	    <textobject>
	      <para>
		Wiki Page
	      </para>
	    </textobject>
	  </mediaobject>
	</figure>
	The wiki is maintained on <filename>github</filename> which keeps a
	historical record and allows easy rollback of changes if necessary.
      </para>
    </section>
  </section>
