<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Michigan_2010_Summary.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
  <section id="sect-Overview">
    <title>Overview</title>
    <para>
      The Michigan Amateur Radio Public Service Corps (ARPSC) is an organization
      of over 2,000 amateur radio operators who participate in public service
      and emergency response activities.  These include such things as providing
      communications for various walks and runs, as well as reporting storm
      damage, participating in search and rescue efforts, and providing backup
      communications for public safety officers.
    </para>
    <para>
      There are two primary programs, the Amateur Radio Emergency Services
      (ARES) and the National Traffic System (NTS).  ARES provides "feet on the
      ground" for various events and incidents, while NTS provides a
      communications infrastructure that moves formal messages acroos the state
      and across the nation.
    </para>
    <para>
      There are two other programs, associated with ARES, which do not report
      independently.  These are RACES and SKYWARN.  RACES consists of those ARES
      members who have been approved by their local government to operate in
      critical areas such as incident scenes or Emergency Operations Centers.
      This approval generally requires a degree of training and a background
      check.  The Michigan Section and the Michigan State Police have published
      suggested RACES qualifications, but the responsibility for vetting RACES
      members rests with the local Emergency Management Coordinator.  Most
      counties follow the guidelines closely.
    </para>
    <para>
      SKYWARN members provide ground weather observations to their local
      jurisdictions and to the National Weather Service.  SKYWARN member do not
      have to be ARES members, but almost always are, and most counties run
      SKYWARN programs as part of their ARES programs.  SKYWARN observers are
      trained by the National Weather Service.
    </para>
    <para>
      Together, Michigan amateurs reported over 85,000 volunteer hours during
      2010 representing a value of over $1.5 million.
    </para>
  </section>
