<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE Article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
]>

  <chapter>
    <title>General Responsibilities</title>

    <section>
      <title>Team Objectives</title>
      <para>
	Auxcomm is present at the SEOC to provide backup communications
	between the area of an incident or emergency and the various state
	agencies.  The "agency coordinator" (SEC or alternate) sits in on the
	EOC proceedings and stays alert to communications needs of the other
	agencies.  The station staff operates the radio station at the direction
	of the coordinator, but, depending on the incident status, may need to
	provide status information and/or direction to the coordinator.
      </para>
      <para>
	Because emergencies are by nature unpredictable, the specific actions
	taken by all team members must necessarily react to the incident.
	Leadership and creativity are required at all levels, and each
	participant must be willing to help the others as the need arises.
      </para>
      <para>
	In order to meet the communications needs of the incident, resources are
	required at the SEOC station as well as in the field.  The station
	manager is responsible for recruiting operators for the SEOC station and
	marshalling those operators as needed.  The Emergency Coordinator in the
	affected area is primarily responsible for local resources.  However,
	should the capabilities of the local county be exceeded, the SEC or
	alternate must marshall additional resources, typically by contacting
	the DEC of the affected area, adjacent DECs or in some cases, nearby ECs
	directly. In addition, the MARS State Director, CAP
	Communications Director or SATERN may be contacted for assistance.
      </para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Resource Needs</title>
      <para>
	The SEC or alternate is the top ranking ARES official for the incident.
	As a consequence, it falls to him to ensure that the event is adequately
	staffed.  Depending on the needs of the particular incident, this will
	require contacting other individuals around the state, and perhaps
	applying some persuasion to achieve the desired result.
      </para>
      <para>
	Most commonly, the SEC will contact the DEC for the area affected by the
	incident.  The DEC is aware of the resources of the affected county and
	the surrounding counties.  If the EC can be reached, he is typically the
	most able to respond quickly.  However, when an incident is underway,
	the EC can often be difficult to reach.
      </para>
      <para>
	At times the local DEC is unreachable or has exhausted all resources.
	The SEC must then exploit the resources of other Districts.  Nearby
	Districts are obviously preferred due to travel times, but any District
	may have the needed resources and must be considered.
      </para>
      <para>
	SATERN, if needed, will typically already be on site.  Local
	Emergency Management Coordinators typically have close contact
	with their local Salvation Army, who in turn will understand
	whether SATERN resources may be helpful.
      </para>
      <para>
	MARS and CAP are a different issue.  They require Federal
	authorization, and unless other arrangements have previously
	been made for the incident, will need to be activated through
	the MSP Dispatch desk.  If needed, the local EMC should be
	contacted, the procedure explained, and a request to MSP made
	from the local jurisdiction.
      </para>
    </section>


  </chapter>
