<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE Article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
]>

<chapter>
  <title>E-Team</title>

  <section>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <para>
	The coordinator should establish an agency SitRep immediately
	on entering the SEOC.  The same SitRep will be maintained by
	the coordinator and the station.  Encourage the station to
	make frequent updates when contacts are made relevant to the
	incident.  The coordinator's updates will typically be
	summaries of station activities as well as information on
	other leadership the coordinator has contacted by telephone.
      </para>
      <para>
	It is important to many agencies to be alert to the state of readiness
	of the RACES station. Agencies have discovered that their communications
	circuits are sometimes fragile, and they may require our services.  An
	up to date and accurate SitRep gives them some confidence about our
	status. 
      </para>
      <para>
	In any case, be sure the Agency SitRep is complete, accurate, and up to
	date.  The SitRep should be updated at least once per hour.
      </para>
    </section>
    <section>
    <title>Logging On</title>
    <para>
      <itemizedlist>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    Log on to E-Team using the password provided by the DIT rep
	    (typically Rich Law or Jaclyn Barcroft).  They will usually log
	    you on.
	    <warning>
	      <title>Use SEOC-specific password</title>
	      <para>
		<!-- This is a real hack but I was having no joy in
		getting this straightened out in the xsl -->
		&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 
		&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 
	      Do not use your personal password when logging on at
		&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 
		&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 
		&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;
	      the SEOC.
	      </para>
	    </warning>
	  </para>
	</listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Initial Duties</title>
    <para>
      <itemizedlist>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    Review the incident report
	  </para>
	</listitem>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    Add an Agency SitRep
	  </para>
	</listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Repetitive Duties</title>
    <para>
      <itemizedlist>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    Update the agency sitrep approximately hourly. Often, the
	    SEOC rep and the station will share a SitRep.
	  </para>
	</listitem>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    Add Duty Log entries if needed (typically not required)
	  </para>
	</listitem>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    Review the incident report and other agency SitReps
	  </para>
	</listitem>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    Be certain to review all numbered messages from message
	    control, either paper copies distributed to the auxcomm
	    desk or on E-Team.
	  </para>
	</listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </para>
  </section>
</chapter>
