<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE Article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
]>

  <chapter>
    <title>Specific Duties</title>

    <section>
      <title>Checking In</title>
      <para>
	On arrival, sign in at the front door.  The door to the
	downstairs stairway will be locked.  If the rep or alternate
	does not have a pass card, an officer will escort him to the
	security station.
      </para>
      <para>
	The rep must pick up a badge at the security station outside
	the EOC room for some events.  Once appropriately signed in,
	enter the EOC, pick up the copy of the position manual in the
	bookshelf near the door, and go to the Auxcomm desk (first
	desk to the right when entering the SEOC).
      </para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Assessing the situation</title>
      <para>
	The rep must first get a feel for the current situation.  Sign
	on to the <application>MI CIMS</application> and quickly
	review the <filename>Incident Action Plan</filename>, if one
	is available.  Also, review the most recent entries in the
	<application>SEOC Significant Events</application> and the
	<application>Statewide Significant Events</application>
	boards.
      </para>
      <para>
	This should be done quickly so that the jurisdiction
	can be contacted.  Often there will be considerable detail to
	be studied, but first the jurisdiction must be contacted.
      </para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Contact local jurisdiction</title>
      <para>
	When the SEOC has been activated, one of the first tasks is to
	contact the DEC for the affected jurisdiction.  In many cases,
	of course, the DEC may have contacted the SEC in the first
	place.  Even in those cases, contact the DEC so (s)he is aware
	that the SEOC is activated.
      </para>
      <para>
	The local ECs affected must also be notified.  When speaking
	with the DEC, decide whether the DEC will notify the ECs or
	whether they will each get a call from Collins Road.
      </para>
      <para>
	Be sure to determine, whether through the DEC or directly with
	the ECs, the communications circuits to be used between the
	SEOC and the local EOC.
      </para>
    </section>
    
    <section>
      <title>Liaison with the station</title>
      <para>
	One of the rep's primary function is to provide a
	communications path between the station status and the various
	agencies.
	<itemizedlist>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
	      Apprise the various agencies of the current station status if
	      needed
	    </para>
	  </listitem>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
	      Communicate the current status of the field situation, as
	      understood by the SEOC, to the station.
	    </para>
	  </listitem>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
	      Alert the station of any communications needs of the agencies.
	    </para>
	  </listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
	If possible, spend some time with the operators prior to the exercise to
	understand the situation there.
      </para>
      <para>
	The coordinator will typically communicate with the station via
	telephone.  See Appendix A for numbers.
      </para>
      <para>
	The coordinator and the station should also agree on a backup
	communications plan.  Typically, the coordinator and a station
	op should have HTs.  A simplex channel should be agreed upon
	since the station's primary VHF radio will likely be
	monitoring a repeater involved in, or relaying for, the
	incident.
      </para>
      <para>
	Stay in regular touch with the station; be aware of their
	situation and whether they are in contact with the site.  Keep
	them up to date as to site changes as announced in the SEOC.
      </para>
      <para>
	If the MARS station is active, be sure to stay abreast of the
	MARS SitRep and include them in hourly updates.  Similarly if
	REACT, CAP or other services are involved.
      </para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Requests</title>
      <para>
	From time to time, the Logistics chief or the Ops chief may
	ask for status information from the field or other
	communications into the affected area.  Be aware of the
	available circuits and field resources so that these requests
	may be routed most effectively.  Keep in mind that event
	though their resources are limited, MARS may well have
	personnel in an appropriate position to respond to the
	request. 
      </para>
      <para>
	Often, we are the only agency with a communications focus. In
	effect, the AuxComm EMC becomes the Communications Branch
	leader. Do not be surprised if the request is far outside a
	simple radiogram, and consider both your unique skills, and
	the considerable resources available at the SEOC to respond to
	the request.
      </para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Agency Announcements</title>
      <para>
	Periodically, the Director or Ops Section Chief will ask for
	agency updates.  Give a brief status of the station for each
	update.  Keep in mind that the agency reps are non-technical,
	but most realize that we are their backup plan.  Give a
	meaningful status without getting technical.  Where possible
	get information on the program status at the local
	jurisdiction and, if significant, pass this along to the other
	agencies as well.
      </para>
      <para>
	Pay attention to the other agency reports.  Should they need
	us our job will be eased if we at least have some familiarity
	with their situation.
      </para>
      <para>
	Consider updating the station with any interesting items from
	the other agencies.  Depending on the drill and players, there
	may be EOCs on the converse bridge unaware of the situation at
	the site and in need of update.
      </para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Debrief</title>
      <para>
	At the end of the exercise, there will be a debrief from all
	agencies.  Prior to this check with the station operators to
	be sure you are aware of any contact with the site or nearby
	jurisdictions.  Often, the station operators may be invited
	into the SEOC for the final debrief.
      </para>
      <para>
	Make a positive, brief presentation when asked.  As usual, avoid
	technical details and focus on capability.
      </para>
    </section>
  </chapter>
