<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE Article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
]>

  <chapter>
    <title>Specific Duties</title>

    <section>
      <title>Checking In</title>
      <para>
	On arrival, sign in at the front door.  The door to the
	downstairs stairway will be locked.  If the rep or alternate
	does not have a pass card, an officer will escort him to the
	security station.
      </para>
      <para>
	The rep must pick up a badge at the security station outside
	the EOC room.  Because of ovecrowding at the SEOC, RACES often
	does not have a designated position.  Select a position that
	is available.
      </para>
    </section>
    
    <section>
      <title>Liaison with the station</title>
      <para>
	The rep's primary function is to provide a communications path between
	the station status and the various agencies.
	<itemizedlist>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
	      Apprise the various agencies of the current station status if
	      needed
	    </para>
	  </listitem>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
	      Communicate the current status of the field situation, as
	      understood by the SEOC, to the station.
	    </para>
	  </listitem>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
	      Alert the station of any communications needs of the agencies.
	    </para>
	  </listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
	If possible, spend some time with the operators prior to the exercise to
	understand the situation there.
      </para>
      <para>
	Ideally, the rep will have an HT and will agree with the station
	on an available frequency.  Note that the station's VHF radio
	will likely be in use, so communication between the rep and the
	station will probably be HT to HT.
      </para>
      <para>
	If HTs are not available or do not work, the telephone may be
	used.  Keep in mind, however, that the SEOC rep will likely not
	have the same number as in previous drills.  Be sure the station
	has the number.
      </para>
      <para>
	Stay in regular touch with the station; be aware of their
	situation and whether they are in contact with the site.  Keep
	them up to date as to site changes as announced in the SEOC.
      </para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Agency Announcements</title>
      <para>
	Periodically, the IC or Ops Section Chief will ask for agency updates.
	Give a brief status of the station for each update.  Keep in mind that the
	agency reps are non-technical, but most realize that we are their backup
	plan.  Give a meaningful status without getting technical.
      </para>
      <para>
	Pay at least passing attention to the other agency reports.
	Should they need us our job will be eased if we at least have
	some familiarity with their situation.
      </para>
      <para>
	Consider updating the station with any interesting items from
	the other agencies.  Depending on the drill and players, there
	may be EOCs on the converse bridge unaware of the situation at
	the site and in need of update.
      </para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Debrief</title>
      <para>
	At the end of the exercise, there will be a debrief from all
	agencies.  Prior to this check with the station operators to be
	sure you are aware of any contact with the site or nearby
	jurisdictions.
      </para>
      <para>
	Make a positive, brief presentation when asked.  As usual, avoid
	technical details and focus on capability.
      </para>
    </section>
  </chapter>
