<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Net_Procedures.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="chap-Net_Procedures-CheckingIn">
  <title>Checking In</title>
    <indexterm><primary>Checking In</primary></indexterm>
  <para>
    The check-in procedure is a members' initial experience with the net, and
    happens to be a place where the different nets vary widely.  Differences in
    expectation among net members during the check in procedure often cause
    confusion and wasted time.  This is an area where most nets should strive to
    be as consistent as possible.
  </para>

  <section id="sect-Net_Procedures-CheckingIn-Preamble">
    <title>Preamble</title>
    <indexterm><primary>Preamble</primary></indexterm>
    <para>
      Most nets have some sort of a preamble, ranging from fairly terse to quite
      lengthy.  The preamble does serve to welcome passers-by to the net and to
      establish the net purpose.
    </para>
    <para>
      Net Managers might take some time to evaluate whether their preamble
      really serves the net.  For a hard-core traffic net is a lengthy preamble
      really all that productive?  For a net with a more social purpose, does
      the preamble serve as an invitation to new members?  Nets might consider
      how appropriate their preamble is to their objectives.  This is a place
      where diversity might be welcomed, but nets should periodically evaluate
      their preamble against the net objectives, and be willing to change when
      appropriate.
    </para>
    <para>
      Once having become comfortable that the preamble is appropriate, net
      managers should be sure that all net controls or potential net controls
      have access to the agreed upon preamble.  Many nets have websites that
      could provide a reference location for net controls; if not, the STM would
      be happy to provide space on the <command>mi-nts</command> website.
    </para>
  </section>

  <section id="sect-Net_Procedures-CheckingIn-Sequence">
    <title>Sequence</title>
      <indexterm>
	<primary>Checking In</primary>
	<secondary>Sequence</secondary>
      </indexterm>
      <indexterm>
	<primary>Checking In</primary>
	<secondary>Order</secondary>
      </indexterm>
      <indexterm>
	<primary>Training Topics</primary>
	<secondary>Checking In</secondary>
      </indexterm>
      <indexterm>
	<primary>Announcements</primary>
	<secondary>Checking In</secondary>
      </indexterm>
      <indexterm>
	<primary>Emergency Traffic</primary>
	<secondary>Checking In</secondary>
      </indexterm>
    <para>
      The order in which check-ins are requested is something that varies
      greatly from net to net, and, in the opinion of the STM, is not a place
      where diversity is useful or welcome.
    </para>
    <para>
      The following order is proposed as a standard (phone proceures shown):
      <orderedlist>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    <application>Is there any emergency or priority
	    traffic?</application>
	  </para>
	</listitem>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    <application>Are there any mobile, portable, QRP or light copy
	    stations for the net?</application>
	  </para>
	</listitem>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    <application>Do we have a liaison from <replaceable>The Michigan
	    Net</replaceable>?</application>  Repeat for each net which
	    typically sends a liaison.
	  </para>
	</listitem>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    <application>Are there any liaisons I did not call or who are late
	    in arriving?</application>
	  </para>
	</listitem>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    <application>Are there any announcements for the net</application>
	  </para>
	</listitem>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    <application>Are there any stations with Training Topics for the
	    net?</application> (Training topics and announcements should be
	    listed early, but not passed until later.  Typically, announcements
	    should be passed before routine traffic but after all checkins,
	    training topics after all traffic has been passed.)
	  </para>
	</listitem>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    <application>Stations with traffic and traffic only, call signs only
	    please</application> After obtaining a list of stations with
	    traffic, NCS should then ask each station to list traffic:
	    <application><replaceable>KB8QWQ</replaceable> please
	    list</application> 
	  </para>
	</listitem>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    <application>Are there any stations with or without
	    traffic?</application> 
	  </para>
	</listitem>
      </orderedlist>
	<indexterm><primary>Over</primary></indexterm>
	<indexterm><primary>Out</primary></indexterm>
      The <application>Over</application> and <application>Out</application>
      prosigns are generally omitted during the checkin procedure as the very
      specific wording used makes them redundant.  The exception is when a
      checkin is listing traffic; the end of the list should be marked by
      <application>Over</application> since the station expects NCS to confirm
      they have the list. 
    </para>
    <para>
	<indexterm><primary>CW</primary></indexterm>
      CW procedures are slightly different.  CW tends to be quite terse, so the
      time spent can be quite short on some things.  On CW, general checkins
      send a single character, usually the first character of their suffix.  NCS
      then queries that station by sending the character, and the station then
      sends their callsign followed by their traffic rather than listing
      seperately. Net liaisons respond by immediately sending their callsign and
      traffic.  
    </para>
    <para>
      The one inefficiency introduced in CW nets is the greeting.
      <orderedlist>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    NCS: <command>E/P QTC? K</command>
	  </para>
	  <para>
	    QNI: <command>GE <replaceable>JOE</replaceable> DE
	    <replaceable>KC8PMX</replaceable> QTC <replaceable>LANSING 1
	    P</replaceable> K</command>
	  </para>
	  <para>
	    NCS: <command><replaceable>KC8PMX</replaceable> GE
	    <replaceable>RYAN</replaceable> R AS QSP
	    <replaceable>LANSING</replaceable> P? K</command>
	  </para>
	</listitem>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    NCS: <command>QNI M/P/QRP? K</command>
	  </para>
	</listitem>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    NCS: <command><replaceable>MVTN</replaceable> REP K</command>
	  </para>
	  <para>
	    QNI: <command>DE <replaceable>KC8RTW</replaceable> GE
	    <replaceable>JOE</replaceable> QRU K</command>
	  </para>
	  <para>
	    NCS: <command><replaceable>KC8RTW</replaceable> GE
	    <replaceable>PAT</replaceable> AS</command>
	  </para>
	</listitem>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    CW nets do not ask for late or uncalled liaisons.  However, liaisons
	    who are late joining will repond to the call for general QNI with a
	    note that they represent a net, for example:
	  </para>
	  <para>
	    <command>DE <replaceable>K0VP/8RN</replaceable> GE
	    <replaceable>JOE</replaceable> QRU K</command>
	  </para>
	  <para>
	    Similarly, if an important downstream net, particularly Eighth
	    Region or NWS, is missing, a station may volunteer to go to that
	    net: 
	  </para>
	  <para>
	    <command>DE <replaceable>K8AE</replaceable> VOL
	    <replaceable>NWS</replaceable> GE <replaceable>JOE</replaceable> QRU
	    K</command>
	  </para>
	</listitem>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    <command>QNC? K</command>
	  </para>
	</listitem>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    On CW nets, training topics are generally introduced as QNCs.  Since
	    traffic is often handled off-frequency on CW nets, net control needs
	    to plan the QNC for a time when all or most stations are checked in,
	    and all are on frequency.
	  </para>
	</listitem>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    On CW, nets do not ask for stations with and without traffic
	    separately.  Because most stations operate QSK or semi-QSK, several
	    stations may check in almost simultaneously and NCS can often handle
	    it. General checkins will also indicate their ability to handle
	    already listed traffic.
	  </para>
	  <para>
	    NCS: <command>QNI K</command>
	  </para>
	  <para>
	    QNI: <command>S</command>
	  </para>
	  <para>
	    QNI: <command>R</command>
	  </para>
	  <para>
	    NCS: <command>R</command>
	  </para>
	  <para>
	    QNI: <command>DE <replaceable>KB8RWG</replaceable> GE
	    <replaceable>JOE</replaceable> QTC
	    <replaceable>SAGINAW 1</replaceable> QSP
	    <replaceable>TAWAS</replaceable> K</command>
	  </para>
	  <para>
	    NCS: <command><replaceable>KB8RWG</replaceable> GE
	    <replaceable>KELLY</replaceable> R AS</command>
	  </para>
	  <para>
	    NCS: <command>S</command>
	  </para>
	  <para>
	    QNI: <command>GE <replaceable>JOE</replaceable> DE
	    <replaceable>W8SN</replaceable> QRU K</command>
	  </para>
	  <para>
	    NCS: <command><replaceable>W8SN</replaceable> GE
	    <replaceable>STAN</replaceable> AS</command>
	  </para>
	  <para>
	    On CW, NCS may immediately send stations off frequency to pass
	    traffic: 
	  </para>
	  <para>
	    QNI: <command>DE <replaceable>KB8RWG</replaceable> GE
	    <replaceable>JOE</replaceable> QTC
	    <replaceable>SAGINAW 1</replaceable> QSP
	    <replaceable>TAWAS</replaceable> K</command>
	  </para>
	  <para>
	    NCS: <command>GE <replaceable>KELLY KB8RWG</replaceable> ES
	    <replaceable>K8SB</replaceable></command>
	  </para>
	  <para>
	    K8SB: <command>T</command>
	  </para>
	  <para>
	    NCS: <command><replaceable>UP 3 UP 3 TAWAS 1
	    K</replaceable></command>
	  </para>
	  <para>
	    KB8RWG: <command>G</command>
	  </para>
	  <para>
	    K8SB: <command>G</command>
	  </para>
	  <para>
	    NCS: <command>TU</command>
	  </para>
	</listitem>
      </orderedlist>
    </para>
  </section>
  
  <section id="sect-Net_Procedures-CheckingIn-ThisIs">
    <title>This Is</title>
    <indexterm><primary>This Is</primary></indexterm>
    <indexterm><primary>FM</primary></indexterm>
    <indexterm><primary>SSB</primary></indexterm>
    <para>
      It has become common practice on phone to follow the MARS procedure of
      saying <application>This is</application>, releasing the microphone for a
      second, and then following with a call.  While there may be some utility
      on MARS circuits, on amateur circuits this procedure offers little or no
      benefit, and merely wastes time and adds confusion.
    </para>
    <para>
      On SSB, net control can tell there is a double, and in most cases can
      identify both stations.  Since <application>This is</application> and most
      call signs take almost identical amounts of time with most speakers,
      neither transmitting station realizes they are doubling since on phone,
      unlike CW, stations cannot hear while they are transmitting.
    </para>
    <para>
      On FM repeaters, the situation is further aggravated by the long transmit
      turnaround delays on the repeater, and the further annoyance of the beep
      almost guaranteeing that the two stations are going to transmit at
      identical times.
    </para>
    <para>
      Some slight advantage might be gained on FM or AM simplex circuits,
      although it seems unlikely.
    </para>
    <para>
      When net control announces <application>call signs only,
      please</application>, stations should announce their callsign only,
      without other adornment or noise words.
    </para>
  </section>

  <section id="sect-Net_Procedures-CheckingIn-Acknowledgement">
    <title>Acknowledgement</title>
    <indexterm><primary>Acknowledgement</primary></indexterm>
      <indexterm>
	<primary>Checking In</primary>
	<secondary>Acknowledgement</secondary>
      </indexterm>
    <para>
      On phone, net control should acknowldege general checkins in as large a
      group as feasible.  In most cases, stations tend to come in groups, so
      acknowledging stations in groups of 5 or 10 reduces the odds of net
      control doubling with a checking in station, and saves time.
    </para>
    <para>
      When conditions are not good, however, it may make sense to acknowledge
      each checkin individually.  When acknowledging checkins individually, net
      control should strive to be efficient, but still ensure that each station
      understands they have been recognized.  For example:
      <application><replaceable>N8OSL</replaceable> roger,
      next</application>. The check in process can be rather tedious, and it is
      not the time for net control to stretch the process out with unnecessary
      comments.
    </para>
  </section>
  
  <section id="sect-Net_Procedures-CheckingIn-NoTraffic">
    <title>No Traffic</title>
    <indexterm><primary>With Traffic</primary></indexterm>
    <indexterm><primary>No Traffic</primary></indexterm>
    <para>
      When checking in, stations should give their call, and if they have
      traffic, add <application>with traffic</application>.  It has become a
      common, and poor, practice to say <application>no traffic</application>
      when a station has no traffic for the net, but this not only spends
      unnecessary time, but can add confusion.  On noisy HF circuits,
      <application>with traffic</application> and <application>no
      traffic</application> sound very similar.  Much better to simply omit
      <application>no traffic</application>.
    </para>
  </section>
  
</section>
