<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Net_Procedures.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="chap-Net_Procedures-Introduction">
  <title>Introduction</title>
    <indexterm><primary>Michigan Net, The</primary></indexterm>
  <para>
    The Michigan Section maintains a very strong NTS system.  The Michigan Net
    was the first spot frequency net in the nation, perhaps in the world, and
    developed many of the procedures used throughout NTS.  In spite of the
    constant drumbeat of "NTS is dying", Michigan's nets continue to pass more
    traffic year after year, and are continually improving their integration
    into the State of Michigan's emergency response strategy.
  </para>
  <para>
    Each of Michigan's affiliated and unaffiliated nets has its strengths and
    weaknesses.  In an effort to continually improve Michigan's NTS system, this
    document seeks to outline some of the better practices developed by some
    nets in order that others may improve their own operation.
  </para>

  <section id="sect-Net_Procedures-Introduction-Net_Differences">
    <title>Differences between nets</title>
    <indexterm><primary>Michigan Net, The</primary></indexterm>
    <indexterm><primary>QMN</primary></indexterm>
    <indexterm><primary>Michigan Traffic Net</primary></indexterm>
    <para>
      The various nets are each unique.  Some of this uniqueness is valuable,
      some is not.  The greater consistency we can achieve among the Michigan
      nets, the more efficient they will be and the easier it will be for new
      members to join a net.  The point of this document is to identify good
      practices in the hope that the nets will adopt them where appropriate.
    </para>
    <para>
      On the other hand, there are differences between the nets that serve a
      purpose.  Some nets are hard-core traffic nets.  QMN is the prime example,
      with the Michigan Traffic Net not far behind.  At the other extreme are
      nets that focus on fraternity, such as the Wolverine Net.  These nets pass
      little or no traffic.  Some nets have a training component which may be
      important to many of the net's members.  Each net serves a particular
      niche.
    </para>
  </section>
  
  <section id="sect-Net_Procedures-Introduction-Members">
    <title>Net Members</title>
    <para>
      One important distinction between the nets is that they serve different
      constituencies.  Many net members feel that handling traffic is boring and
      takes time away from the important business of the net.  Others find the
      idle chit-chat to be a waste of time, and want to get the traffic passed
      as efficiently as possible.
    </para>
    <para>
      One thing is consistent among these members, however; when traffic is
      passed, it should be passed as expiditiously as possible.  Hard-core
      traffic handlers pride themselves on efficiency.  Those less interested in
      traffic handling want to get it out of the way as quickly as possible.
    </para>
  </section>

</section>

