<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
]>

  <section id="chap-Net_Procedures-NetBiz">
    <title>Net Business</title>
    <para>
      There is considerable variation in the way the nets in the Section conduct
      business.  In most cases, there is no need for these differences.
    </para>

    <section id="sect-Net_Procedures-NetBiz-Announcements">
      <title>Announcements</title>
      <indexterm><primary>Announcements</primary></indexterm>
      <indexterm><primary>QNC</primary></indexterm>
      <para>
	Announcements should be made after all checkins, but before other net
	business.  NCS should try to arrange announcements to occur when all (or
	most) of the checkins are present.  Since traffic on CW is generally
	passed off-frequency and often routed as listed, it can take careful
	planning on the part of NCS to ensure all members have an opportunity to
	hear the announcement.
      </para>
    </section>
    
    <section id="sect-Net_Procedures-NetBiz-Traffic">
      <title>Traffic</title>
      <indexterm>
        <primary>Traffic</primary>
	<secondary>Passing</secondary>
      </indexterm>
      <para>
	Traffic should be handled after all checkins and any announcements.
	Some nets are tempted to move traffic during checkins, but this is
	generally not desireable unless traffic is being handled off-frequency.
	Stations want to get checked in as quickly as possible, and leave if
	there is no traffic for them.  Handling traffic on-frequency before all
	stations have checked in simply wastes time for stations that are not
	yet checked in.
      </para>
      <para>
	One obvious exception is when a net liaison has short time.  There are
	occasions when a liaison needs to get traffic for a downstream net
	passed early so that the liaison can get to the downstream net.  On
	phone, it is often difficult to find another frequency to pass that
	traffic, but NCS should endeavor to find an alternate frequency if
	possible. 
      </para>
      <para>
	Net control should consider the most effective way to route the traffic.
	Traffic should be organized to get as many stations done with the net
	business as possible, as early as possible.  When a pair of stations
	have a long list of traffic, that traffic should be handled last in
	order to get other stations checked out.  Obviously, other constraints
	such as later nets and short time stations must be considered.
      </para>
      <para>
	NCS should strive to become familiar with regular checkins and their
	capabilities.  Often, two stations within VHF simplex range can be sent
	to two meters to pass traffic off the net frequency.  Repeaters can be
	used when repeater owners are amenable to using their machines for
	traffic.
      </para>
    </section>
    
    <section id="sect-Net_Procedures-NetBiz-Routing">
      <title>Routing Traffic</title>
      <indexterm>
	<primary>Traffic</primary>
	<secondary>Routing</secondary>
      </indexterm>
      <para>
	Net control should strive to route traffic in an effective fashion, with
	an eye toward sharing the burden where possible.  It can be discouraging
	to show up at a net night after night and have all traffic sent to
	another station.
      </para>
      <para>
	On the other hand, NCS should assume that net liaison stations are
	willing to accept traffic bound for that net.  This is especially true
	of Eighth Region and NWS reps.
      </para>
      <para>
	Some net controls are reluctant to route traffic to stations who will
	deliver it via a calling plan.  Certainly, it is preferable that traffic
	be delivered by a station close to the destination.  However, except for
	HXG traffic, messages should not be delayed simply because the net
	control doesn't like how it will be delivered.  Even HXG traffic should
	not be excessively delayed simply because NCS does not agree with the
	form of delivery.  Nevertheless, it is preferable to find a local
	station for delivery where that does not unduly delay the traffic.
      </para>
    </section>
    
    <section id="sect-Net_Procedures-NetBiz-TT">
      <title>Training Topics</title>
      <para>
	<indexterm><primary>Training Topics</primary></indexterm>
	Some nets have regular training topics.  Generally, these should be
	transmitted after other net business, except in the case of nets whose
	primary purpose is training (e.g. QMN TN).
      </para>
      <para>
	<indexterm><primary>QNC</primary></indexterm>
	Training topics should be introduced as formal QNCs where possible.
	This has a number of advantages:
	<itemizedlist>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
	      The formal QNC sends a signal to the membership that the
	      delivering station has spent the time to prepare the topic in a
	      concise, well-thought-out fashion.
	    </para>
	  </listitem>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
	      Stations have a clean way to file and organize training topics for
	      future reference.
	    </para>
	  </listitem>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
	      Stations also have a convenient way to re-use the training topic
	      in a later training session with a different group.
	    </para>
	  </listitem>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
	      The delivering station has a convenient way of keeping track of
	      what topics have been delivered.
	    </para>
	  </listitem>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
	      Students get the additional practice of copying formal traffic.
	    </para>
	  </listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
      </para>
    </section>
    
    <section id="sect-Net_Procedures-NetBiz-OverOut">
      <title>Over vs. Out</title>
      <indexterm><primary>MARS</primary></indexterm>
      <para>
	The recent influx of MARS members to the nets has caused more amateurs
	to return to the proper use of the prowords
	<application>Over</application> and <application>Out</application> which
	had fallen into disuse in recent years. Net controls should set an
	example for all stations, including appropriate use of these prowords.
	<itemizedlist>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
	      <indexterm><primary>Over</primary></indexterm>
	      <application>Over</application> means "I am finished transmitting
	      and expect a reply from you".
	    </para>
	  </listitem>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
	      <indexterm><primary>Out</primary></indexterm>
	      <application>Out</application> means "I am finished transmitting
	      and I do not expect a direct reply from you".
	    </para>
	  </listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
      </para>
    </section>

    <section id="sect-Net_Procedures-NetBiz-RogerWilco">
      <title>Roger and Wilco</title>
      <para>
	<indexterm><primary>MARS</primary></indexterm>
	<indexterm><primary>Roger</primary></indexterm>
	<indexterm><primary>Wilco</primary></indexterm> Many stations also
	misuse the term <application>Roger</application> which means "I have
	received and understood your transmission".  Recently more stations
	replace the <application>Roger</application> with the MARS term
	<application>Wilco</application>, which means "Will comply".  This is
	the preferred use when your intention is not only to acknowledge
	receipt, but your intention to comply.
      </para>
    </section>
    
  </section>
