<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Net_Procedures.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
  <section id="chap-Net_Procedures-PassingTraffic">
    <title>Passing Traffic</title>
    <section id="sect-Net_Procedures-Passingtraffic-Break">
      <title>Break</title>
      <indexterm>
	<primary>Traffic</primary>
	<secondary>Passing</secondary>
      </indexterm>
      <indexterm><primary>Break</primary></indexterm>
      <indexterm><primary>MARS</primary></indexterm>
      <indexterm><primary>CW</primary></indexterm>
      <para>
	While there tend to be few, if any, net to net differences in the use of
	the word <application>Break</application>, there are operator to
	operator differences. It is significant because MARS usage of the word
	is quite different than amateur radio use.
      </para>
      <para>
	In many cases, amateurs can benefit from observing the generally more
	disciplined MARS practice.  However, in this case, the use of the word
	<application>Break</application> is well-established in amateur radio
	and at odds with MARS use, so stations should be careful to avoid the
	MARS practice in this instance.
      </para>
      <para>
	Further complicating the issue is the fact that
	<application>Break</application> is used entirely differently in the
	context of a formal message than it's use outside a message.
      </para>
      <section>
	<title>Break within a message</title>
	<para>
	  When used within the context of a formal message,
	  <application>Break</application> has almost the same meaning as the CW
	  "double-dash" character; a break between sections of a message.  The
	  <application>Break</application> proword is used between the address
	  and the body of a message, and between the body and the signature.
	</para>
	<para>
	  On phone, <application>Break</application> has the added implication
	  that the sender intends to release the microphone so that the
	  receiving station may ask for fills, although this step is often
	  omitted before the signature.  On CW, this is not necessary since most
	  stations can receive while transmitting.
	</para>
      </section>

      <section>
	<title>Break outside a message</title>
	<para>
	  In amateur practice, a <application>Break</application> outside the
	  context of a formal message means "I need to interrupt this
	  conversation for something important".  <application>Break
	  Break</application> means "I need to interrupt this conversation
	  because of an emergency".  This is rather dramatically different than
	  MARS practice, which is to use <application>Break</application> much
	  the same as inside a message, so stations should be careful to avoid
	  MARS practice and caution others as well.
	</para>
      </section>

    </section>
    
  </section>

