<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Net_Procedures.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
  <section id="chap-Net_Procedures-Technology">
    <title>Technology</title>
    <para>
      In modern amateur radio, many modes and frequencies are in use.  Each mode
      and each band has it's own characteristics.  Net controls and net members
      both need to be alert to these differences, and use them accordingly.
    </para>
    <section id="sect-Net_Procedures-Technology-Mode">
      <title>Mode Characteristics</title>
      <para>
	The greatest differences are between modes.  Each mode has unique
	characteristics that the operator must consider.
      </para>
      <section>
	<title>CW</title>
	<indexterm>
	  <primary>Characteristics</primary>
	  <secondary>CW</secondary>
	</indexterm>
	<indexterm>
	  <primary>CW</primary>
	</indexterm>
	<indexterm>
	  <primary>QSK</primary>
	</indexterm>
	<indexterm>
	  <primary>Break-In</primary>
	</indexterm>
	<indexterm>
	  <primary>Repeats</primary>
	  <secondary>CW</secondary>
	</indexterm>
	<para>
	  On CW, many stations operate QSK or break-in, and virtually all
	  stations at least operate semi-break-in.  This means that the operator
	  can hear the band between elements or at least between words.
	</para>
	<para>
	  On all modes, it generally helps the receiving station to send a few
	  words before beginning the actual message.  On CW, it is common
	  practice to precede the message number with <command>NR</command> or
	  <command>HR NR</command> rather than starting right out with the
	  message number.  When a station is operating break-in and is
	  comfortable with that, the station may instead start with <command>QSK
	    NR</command> to indicate to the receiver that the sender may be
	  interrupted in the middle of the message to get fills.
	</para>
	<para>
	  When sending a surprising or unusual word, the sender may send a
	  <command>?</command> character following the word and then repeat the
	  word.  This is the equivalent of the phone <application>I say
	    again</application>. 
	</para>
	<para>
	  The "official" eight dits as an error indication is rarely used.  Most
	  stations send two I's (didit didit) then repeat the mis-sent word.
	  Sometimes when the error should be obvious, the sender simply re-sends
	  the word.
	</para>
	<para>
	  On CW, it is the norm, rather than the exception, to pass traffic off
	  the main net frequency.
	</para>
      </section>
      <section>
	<title>SSB</title>
	<indexterm>
	  <primary>Characteristics</primary>
	  <secondary>SSB</secondary>
	</indexterm>
	<indexterm>
	  <primary>SSB</primary>
	</indexterm>
	<indexterm>
	  <primary>Phonetic Alphabet</primary>
	</indexterm>
	<indexterm>
	  <primary>Repeats</primary>
	  <secondary>SSB</secondary>
	</indexterm>
	<para>
	  SSB is especially challenging because of the poor voice quality and
	  the typically poor band conditions.  Unlike CW, the sending station
	  cannot hear the receiving station, so it is imperative that the sender
	  give appropriate breaks to ask for fills, especially when conditions
	  are poor.
	</para>
	<para>
	  On SSB circuits, it is common to spell unusual or unexpected words, or
	  even common words that are easily confused.  The proper practice is to
	  give the word, say <application>I spell</application> and then say the
	  word again.  For example, "<application><replaceable>two</replaceable>
	  I spell <replaceable>Tango Whiskey Oscar
	  two</replaceable></application>".  When the word is surprising, but
	  not easily confused with another and the spelling is obvious, the
	  sender will use <application>I say again</application>, for example,
	  "<application><replaceable>artichoke</replaceable> I say again
	  <replaceable>artichoke</replaceable></application>".
	</para>
	<para>
	  Because of the difficult conditions often encoutnered on SSB, it is
	  important to use the precise phrase, rather than some made-up phrase.
	  Similarly, it is important to use the proper ICAO phonetics, rather
	  than using some less common phonetic alphabet, or worse still,
	  something invented on the fly.
	</para>
	<para>
	  Like CW, an operator can tell when two stations are transmitting
	  simultaneously, and often can understand both.  The transmitting
	  station, however, cannot tell if another station is transmitting.
	</para>
	<para>
	  On phone, the equivalent of the CW <command>HR NR</command> is
	  <application>Please copy number</application>. On SSB especially it is
	  important to use the exact phrasing to reduce misunderstanding.
	</para>
      </section>
      <section>
	<title>FM and AM</title>
	<indexterm>
	  <primary>FM</primary>
	</indexterm>
	<indexterm>
	  <primary>Characteristics</primary>
	  <secondary>FM</secondary>
	</indexterm>
	<indexterm>
	  <primary>AM</primary>
	</indexterm>
	<indexterm>
	  <primary>Characteristics</primary>
	  <secondary>AM</secondary>
	</indexterm>
	<indexterm>
	  <primary>Heterodyne</primary>
	</indexterm>
	<indexterm>
	  <primary>Capture Effect</primary>
	</indexterm>
	<para>
	  FM detectors exhibit a characteristic known as the "capture effect",
	  meaning that when two stations are transmitting, the listener will
	  only hear the strongest signal.  Sometimes when the two signals are
	  close in strength, the listner will hear a hetrodyne, but unlike SSB,
	  only one station, at most, will be intelligible.  On AM, multiple
	  stations will cause a heterodyne, but unless their signal strengths
	  are greatly different, neither will be understood.
	</para>
	<para>
	  This effect means that efficiencies possible on SSB are not possible
	  on FM or AM.  Stations, especially net controls, should recognize that
	  weaker stations will be totally obscured by stronger stations.  On the
	  other hand, some of this disadvantage is offset by the superior audio
	  quality available on FM and AM.
	</para>
	<para>
	  FM detectors take some time to capture the signal, and thus a receiver
	  might miss the first few milliseconds of a transmission.  A repeater
	  as a minimum multiplies that effect since the repeater has a receiver
	  too.  In addition, many repeaters have short timers before they begin
	  transmissions to eliminate false transmissions resulting from noise.
	  Because of these effects, FM operators in particular should wait a
	  second or so after keying the microphone before speaking.  Repeater
	  users should become familiar with their machines as some repeaters may
	  require several seconds of delay.
	</para>
      </section>
      <section>
	<title>Packet</title>
	<indexterm>
	  <primary>Characteristics</primary>
	  <secondary>Packet</secondary>
	</indexterm>
	<indexterm>
	  <primary>Packet</primary>
	</indexterm>
	<para>
	  Packet features "guaranteed" delivery, so many of the adaptations
	  required for other modes are unnecessary on packet.  On packet, a user
	  simply logs into a BBS, types <command>S
	    <replaceable>callsign</replaceable>@<replaceable>hamgate</replaceable>.ampr.org</command>
	  and types in the message.  Instead of the double dash on CW or
	  <application>Break</application> on phone, sections of the message are
	  separated by a blank line.  Messages are separated by two blank
	  lines.  It is common practice to end the entire set of messages with a
	  line containing only <command>NNNN</command>.  The line
	  <command>/EX</command> notifies the BBS of the end of the
	  transmission. 
	</para>
	<para>
	  The message on packet should follow the normal NTS format.  To aid the
	  reciever, it is helpful to format the body of the message with five
	  words per line.  Messages are typically entered entirely in upper
	  case.  As in a normal message, the only punctuation is
	  <command>X</command>. 
	</para>
      </section>
      <section>
	<title>Olivia</title>
	<indexterm>
	  <primary>Characteristics</primary>
	  <secondary>Olivia</secondary>
	</indexterm>
	<indexterm>
	  <primary>Olivia</primary>
	</indexterm>
	<indexterm>
	  <primary>Michigan Digital Traffic Net</primary>
	</indexterm>
	<para>
	  The Michigan Digital Traffic Net (MDTN) is working out the proper
	  procedures for handling traffic using Olivia.  Olivia offers forward
	  error correction, which while not quite as effective as packet,
	  nonetheless offers a significant improvement over many HF digital
	  modes.
	</para>
	<para>
	  Like FM, neither the transmitting station nor the receiving station
	  can copy multiple stations simulataneously.  Olivia, like all digital
	  modes featuring forward error correction, exhibits a significant delay
	  between a character being sent and received.  This requires different
	  net procedures that are still in the process of being worked out.
	</para>
      </section>
    </section>
    
  </section>

